U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records 5039
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records
1926-1951
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5039
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcript of proceedings and exhibits, Emergency Board No. 98, 1951. Union shop case. Seventeen cooperating (non-operative) railway labor organizations and 390 carriers, most combined for representation by Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees, 1926-1952.
3114266
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 05, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Emergency Board created under the President's Executive Order #10155 dated November 15, 1951, was composed of Mr. David L. Cole, labor consultant, Patterson, N.J., as Chairman: Mr. Aaron Horwitz, Attorney, New York City, and Mr. George E. Osborne, Professor of Law, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California. Hearings were held in Washington, D. C., from December 11 to 17, 1951 and January 8 to 29, 1952.
The report to the President on February 14, 1952, recommended that:
1. The parties enter into a Joint National Agreement, through their duly designated representatives in accordance with the usual custom, providing for a union-shop agreement as proposed by the organizations in their notices of February 5, 1951, to the several carriers, parties to this dispute, in the form substantially as used in the union-shop agreements; with the New York Central System Lines, with certain exceptions
2. The afore-mentioned Joint national Agreement to provide for the deduction of dues, initiation fees, and assessments and that the details be worked out in substantially the same manner as is provided for in the agreement of August 3, 1951, between the New York Central Railroad System Lines and these organizations, with certain modifications.
Among the exceptions recommended by the Emergency Board were:
1. That all positions not represented by the organization, all fully excepted positions, and all positions covered in the scope rule only in a nominal or token manner, be covered by a union shop agreement
2. Provide that no claims against the carrier shall arise or begin to accrue in favor of a discharged employee or any other employee or the union prior to a final determination of the dispute, such time to include the time during which action against the carrier is stayed by any court.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5006: U.S. Emergency Board No. 174 Records 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5030: U.S. Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material 5036: U.S. Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports 5037: U.S. Emergency Board No. 81 Records 5038: U.S. Emergency Board No. 94 Records 5040: U.S. Emergency Board No. 106 Records 5042: U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records 5043: U.S. Emergency Board No. 114 Records 5044: U.S. Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits 5045: U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records 5046: U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records 5047: U.S. Emergency Board No. 120 Records 5048: U.S. Emergency Board No. 121 Records 5050: U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records 5051: U.S. Emergency Board No. 125 Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5053: U.S. Emergency Board No. 130 Records 5054: U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5055: U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5056: U.S. Emergency Board No. 135 Records 5057: U.S. Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5058: U.S. Emergency Board No. 138 Records 5059: U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records 5060: U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records 5061: U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records 5062: U.S. Emergency Board No. 154 Records 5064: U.S. Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5075: U.S. Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5934: Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219
Collective bargaining -- Railroads -- United States; Open and closed shop -- United States; United States. Emergency Board No. 98
3114266
- Transcripts. Carrier Exhibits. (Box 1)
  - Transcripts. 21 Volumes. 2188 Pages. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. Index to the record and summary of the evidence. Brief filed on behalf of certain Western Carriers and the Pullman Company (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Carrier Exhibits 1 and 2 as listed in the transcript are missing, but all exhibits listed here are included.
  - 1a. Brief on behalf of 31 Southwestern Carriers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2. Memorandum brief filed by Eastern and Western Carriers on the Right to Strike and its relation to the function of an Emergency Board (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2a. Summary of opening statement by Donald Richberg. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1. Constitutions of the 17 unions involved and the Railway Employees Department (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2. Circular 1823, of January 29, issued to all general chairmen by Leighty (Box 1, Folder 7)
    No year listed
  - W3. The Union Shop Amendment to the Railway Labor Act is Unconstitutional (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - W4. Union shop agreements with these organizations would operate to deprive railroad employees of their constitutional rights (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - E5. The handling of union shop demand (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - E6. Supervisory employees (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - E7. Rules governing classification of railroad employees (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - E7a. Pennsylvania Railroad Monthly Report of Employees, Service and Compensation (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - E8. Exclusions from the union shop agreements in the railroad industry (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - E9. Exclusion from coverage of collective bargaining agreements in industries other than railroads (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - E10. Analysis of exclusions from agreements containing Union Shop, Modified Union Shop, or Maintenance of Membership Provisions - Industries other than railroads (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - E11. Employers' protection clauses in union security agreements (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - E12. Universal Declaration of Human Rights (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - W13. Agreement between Chancellor Canfield Midway Oil Company and the Oil Workers International Union (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - W14. Job classification and geographical location of employees of Santa Fe protesting execution of Union Shop Agreements (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - W15. State involving union shop agreements (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - W16. Scope rules of agreements covering clerical groups and supervisors in Maintenance of Way and Structures Departments (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - E17. Number of employees included in selected reporting divisions (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - E18. Classification of railroad employees involved in Union Shop request of the 17 cooperating Railway Labor organizations, number of employees on 26 Eastern railroads who should be excluded from any union security provisions (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - W19. Selected provisions of the Constitutions and by-laws of the 17 cooperating labor organizations (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - W20. Confidential, supervisory and other responsible positions in Southern Pacific Company's various departments, now wholly, or partially subject to craft agreements, occupants of which should not be compelled to maintain union membership (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - W21. Text of scope rules - clerks' agreements, Western Region (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - W22. Variations in agreement coverages of non-operating employees on certain Western railroads (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - W23. Table showing voting strength of affiliated unions from the report of the American Federation of Labor, Executive Board (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - W24. National Railroad Adjustment Board Third Division Award, 3916 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - W25. National Railroad Adjustment Board Third Divisions Award, 4060 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - W26. Interpretation of the Great Northern Award (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - W27. National Railroad Adjustment Board Third Division Award, 4660 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - W28. Union security in the railroad industry (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - W29. Opposition of compulsory unionism in the United States (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - W30. Law of the State of Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - W31. Bureau of Labor Statistics studies on union security (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - W32. Union membership requirements in the airline contracts negotiated since the Railway Labor Act was amended (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - W33. Compulsory unionism in foreign countries (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - W34. The Union Shop would give officials monopolistic and autocratic powers and subject the carriers, their employees and the general public to the hazards of arbitrary and despotic actions (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - W35. National Railroad Adjustment Board Third Division Award, 4087 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - W36. National Mediation Board Representation Certificates, 1943-1951 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - W37. Admission policies of labor unions (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - W38. Initiation Fees (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - S39. Union shop contracts with the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - 40. Brief outline of employees position on Legal Arguments of Southeastern Carriers (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - 41. Statement of the Committee of: a. A group of members of the Railway Clerks Union. b. A group of non-union railway clerks. c. A group of American citizens opposed to the interruption of commerce. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - 42. Agreement between Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company and Order of Railway Telegraphers, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    July 15, 1949.
  - 43. Memorandum of Understanding, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    March 1, 1948
  - 44. Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company schedule of wages and general regulations, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    October 16, 1948.
  - 45. Memorandum Agreement, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    February 16, 1948
  - 46. Executive Order 19155, possession, control, and operation of certain railroads (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Union Exhibits (Box 2)
  - 1. Notices served requesting union shop and check-off (included in transcript page 87) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1a. Brief for the 17 Cooperating Railway Labor Organizations (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 2. Development of union shop and check-off policy in Federal Railway Labor Legislation and Regulation (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 3. The Union Shop Principle - American Arbitration Association and Arbitration Awards (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 3a. Supplement to the above (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 4. Union shop and check-off provisions in outside industries (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 5. Union shop elections under the Taft-Hartley Act (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 6. Prevalence of union agreements - Railway unions with outside industries (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 7. Union Shop agreements in transportation agencies other than railway (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 8. Union Shop clauses in labor agreements of railway controlled companies (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 9. Security clauses and practices affecting Company Unions (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 10. Membership and dues in Railroad Hospital Association (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 11. Collective bargaining agreements with union shop provisions in the railroad industry (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 11a. Detailed list of railroads which have signed union agreements with one or more of the 17 cooperating labor organizations (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 12. Analysis of carriers statistical data (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 13. The Union Shop and Human Rights (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 14. Company unions in the Railway Industry, 1926-1933 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 15. States Rights under the Railway Labor Act, Amendments, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)